Prologue

At the Galarc Castle, just before the main entrance...

“Please allow me to accompany you on the mission to rescue Lady Liselotte.”

Aria Governess, Liselotte’s head attendant, bowed her head before Rio with deep regret. There was no need to question her motive: Liselotte was her master.

She had an extraordinary amount of loyalty to her—she treasured Liselotte beyond mere loyalty. Seeing how she was dressed in adventurer-like clothes, she must have prepared for this journey in advance. She may have even approached King Francois for permission to leave by herself if Rio hadn’t acted as he did.

It was easy to see the loyalty behind the determination in Aria’s expression. If Rio were to refuse her here, she would simply act independently from him. That would result in her following Rio anyway, as he was capable of tracking Erica from afar.

Ability-wise, there was no concern of Aria becoming a hindrance. She was a reassuring force to have if the situation called for more people. Furthermore, the situation had caused Rio to begin pursuing Saint Erica without hearing the details of what happened. Since he lacked information, having Aria come along would be most beneficial.

The only reason Rio had to refuse her was Aishia. Until now, he had kept her existence as a spirit as secret as possible from any third parties. Since he was using her to track Erica right now, he’d have to reveal her to Aria. However, he didn’t mind. After closing his eyes and thinking for a moment, he prioritized the feelings he could sense coming from Aria and nodded.

“I understand... However, I will require that you follow my orders while we pursue her. Is that all right?”

“Of course. Thank you very much,” Aria said immediately with a low bow.

Haruto, the target sped up dramatically after leaving the gate. She’s heading out of the noble district to avoid attention, said Aishia’s telepathic message.

Got it. Continue trailing her in spirit form.

Understood.

Their conversation wrapped up quickly.

“Let’s go. It seems the saint has sped up,” Rio said to Aria, looking in the direction of the front gate several hundred meters away.

“...Right.” Aria nodded with a slightly surprised look; it was impossible to see outside the grounds from their current position. Rio had claimed to have a method of tracking the saint without being noticed, so she was probably wondering how he knew that.

“I’ll explain the details later. Please enhance yourself with your enchanted sword,” Rio ordered, enhancing his own body at the same time.

“Right.” Aria held back her questions for the moment and grabbed the hilt of her sword, focusing on the task at hand.

“Follow me.”

Rio ran towards the front gate. With Aria at his heels, the two left the Galarc Castle grounds.

Bonus Short Stories

Just for a Little While

One morning in the spirit folk village, in the house where everyone lived with Rio before they all returned to the Strahl region...

Rio himself woke up and left the house to do his daily training routine. “Good morning, Sayo.” He spotted Sayo swinging a wooden training sword all by herself.

“Ah! Good morning, Sir Rio.”

“Looks like you’re first today,” Rio said after checking no one else was around.

Rio’s morning training routine was originally something he started alone at a young age, but after coming to the spirit folk village, he was joined by Sara and the others. After growing older and returning to the Strahl region, Miharu and Celia joined in; now, after reuniting with Sayo and Gouki’s group, they all participated together.

Their routines were all customized for their own specialty areas: Rio and Sara with their weapons, Miharu with spirit arts, and Celia with magic essence control.

In Sayo’s case, she worked on both her weapon and spirit arts. Her training had apparently started back in her home village, but Gouki’s group had given her full-blown training on their journey to the spirit folk village. Her growth was shocking to Rio.

“Yes! I woke up early. I only just started,” Sayo replied energetically, smiling from ear to ear.

“You’re working hard. I’ll join you in swing practice.”

“Please do!”

The two of them swung their swords in silence for a while. But several minutes later...

“...” Sayo stopped swinging and started watching Rio’s movements instead, captivated.

“Is something the matter...?” Noticing her fixed gaze, Rio paused his swings.

“Huh...? Oh, no! Umm...!” Sayo gasped and began to panic. “I just thought your movements were wonderful...” she admitted in embarrassment.

“I’m just swinging my sword like normal.”

“No! When I watch you from the side, your sword comes to a stop so quickly. You’ve perfectly erased any signs of your movement. Now that Sir Gouki is teaching me the proper use of weapons, I understand how amazing you really are...” Sayo said, emphasizing Rio’s skills.

“Ahaha. Thank you,” Rio said bashfully.

“N-No, not at all... Umm, could I watch you swing your sword for a little longer?” Sayo blushed and looked down, her eyes peering upwards at Rio’s face.

“Sure, but it really isn’t that impressive.” Rio nodded with embarrassment, then resumed his swinging. That being said, he wasn’t the type to let himself be flustered enough to mess up his movements.

And so...

“...” For some time after that, Sayo watched Rio with a heated gaze of captivation as he swung his sword. Her face in profile was precisely that of a young maiden in love—it was a look of pure bliss. While the moment between them continued, there was someone secretly watching over them quietly. It was Sayo’s older brother, Shin. He was probably examining the mood in the air for the sake of his sister. He had his own wooden training sword in his hand, yet he didn’t move from the shadows of the trees.

“If it isn’t Shin. What are you doing there?” Gouki arrived to participate in the morning training and discovered him.

“Nothing much...” Shin replied awkwardly.

“Hmm...” Gouki spotted Rio swinging his sword in the distance, and Sayo standing next to him. He seemed to catch on to the situation with just that.

“Haha. I see, I see,” he grinned.

“I said it’s nothing,” Shin snapped to hide his embarrassment, then marched off towards Rio and Sayo.

An Exchange One Morning

The day after Rio and Aria began their pursuit of Saint Erica, the two used the stone house for shelter. It was morning, and Aria had woken up early to prepare breakfast. But when she stepped out of the room she was borrowing, she was greeted with the scent of something delicious wafting from the kitchen.

“Good morning, Aria.” Rio had woken up earlier than her and prepared breakfast.

“Good morning, Sir Amakawa... You’re up rather early.” Aria blinked in surprise. She was hoping to lessen his workload by making breakfast herself, but he had done so first.

“I always get up early to practice with my sword.”

“That’s a wonderful routine.”

“You’re up early as well.”

“I always have work to do in the morning, so it’s a habit for me.”

“I see. I’m almost done preparing breakfast, so please have a seat,” Rio said, resuming his preparations with the ingredients.

“If you don’t mind, I’d like to help out. In fact, I’m willing to prepare all the meals for us while we’re on this trip...”

“You’re the guest in this house, so there’s no need for you to do so.”

“You’re providing the shelter, so it’s only right for me to repay you by doing work,” Aria insisted.

Rio chuckled “Fine... In that case, let’s cook together. I’d feel bad if I just sat back and let you do all the work,” he suggested.

“I understand. I’ll be borrowing an apron, then.”

Aria entered the kitchen and put on one of the aprons hanging there. Thus, Rio and Aria made breakfast together.

Elemental ☆ Alice

In Japan, in the school that Amakawa Haruto and Ayase Miharu attended...

One afternoon in December, Haruto and Miharu were visiting the classroom where the drama club held their activities. They had been summoned there by Satsuki, a member of the student council. Satsuki and two other members of the drama club were waiting in the room for them.

“Huh, so our drama club’s participating in our preschool’s Christmas party.”

Rio and Miharu listened to the explanation from Satsuki.

“Yup. The preschool is attached to our affiliated university rather than us directly, but same deal. They heard we had a drama club, so they asked if we could hold a Christmas party for them.”

“I see. So why were we called here...?” Haruto had a vague idea already, but asked anyway.

“The principal came to the student council with the request. The drama club only has a few members, so the student council is going to take part in the party as well.”

“Does that mean we’re going to appear on stage? Neither Mii-chan nor I have any experience acting...” Haruto said, exchanging a look with Miharu.

“Yeah, that’s what I was hoping to ask. It’s just a simple play to be held in front of young children, so you don’t need to feel overly pressured...”

How about it? Satsuki looked between Haruto and Miharu apologetically.

“Oh, by the way. Professor Celia and Professor Aishia will be joining us from the teaching staff,” she added.

“Huh. What kind of play will it be?”

“Hmm... I haven’t read the script myself, but it’s apparently a reproduction of an old script left from a few years ago. It features characters from all kinds of fairy tales that children would know. Professor Celia and Miss Aishia are in the classroom next door looking at the costumes right now, but...”

Just as Satsuki spoke, the classroom door opened and Aishia entered. “Professor... Aishia?”

“Wow...”

“Oh my, how adorable...”

Miharu and Satsuki let out sounds of awe at the sight of Aishia, who had entered wearing one of the costumes for the play.

“Is that from Alice in Wonderland?” Haruto asked.

“Yup. Does it look good?” Aishia looked at Haruto and cocked her head.

“Yes, very,” Haruto nodded firmly. It really looked good on her.

“Isn’t it lovely?” Celia entered the room after Aishia and joined the conversation.

“Huh? Didn’t you try on any of the costumes, Professor Celia?” Satsuki asked with a playful grin.

“No. I only went to check the condition of the costumes. I didn’t go to try them on.”

“Then why is Miss Aishia in a costume?”

“The kids in the drama club specifically requested it,” Celia explained with a wry smile.

“Ah, I see... But the outfits are a vital part of the play, aren’t they? Why don’t we go take a look as well, Miharu? Haruto?” Satsuki turned to the two of them with a curious glint in her eye.

“Let’s go take a look, Haru-kun.”

“Well... Sure. Okay.”

Miharu invited the slightly embarrassed Haruto along, and they all went to see the outfits together.

Chapter 4: The Saint’s Return

Nearly two weeks had passed since Liselotte was sent to the Holy Democratic Republic of Erica. Ever since the day she was allowed out of the mansion, she was given permission to go outside as long as she was accompanied by Andrei. Otherwise, she remained under confinement.

In spite of that allowance, Liselotte only went out to observe various places for the first few days. She soon stopped going outside, and was instead visited frequently by Andrei in her room.

Part of the reason was because the capital of Ericaburg was a small city with little to see, but it was mostly because their positions had reversed. The original goal was for Liselotte to learn about the Holy Democratic Republic of Erica from Andrei, but somewhere down the line, it turned out Andrei had more to learn from Liselotte.

Liselotte had retained her memories from her past life, gotten a noble-class education in her current life, and served as both the president of a trading guild and city governor for the past few years. Those experiences hadn’t just been for show.

In comparison, Andrei was once the owner of a small business who had only just taken the position of prime minister, so there wasn’t much he could teach Liselotte. He had received a crash course on his position from Saint Erica during the revolution, but it didn’t take long for him to realize that Liselotte had a better education and experience suited for politics.

Andrei started bringing Liselotte questions about governance, and Liselotte went along with the discussions in order to obtain more information. That gave Andrei a favorable and intelligent impression of her, giving her more opportunities to ask her own questions.

“I see. So there’ll be conflict between the rights of the people, you say... The citizens are more aware of their own rights now, so the conflicts will be more intense as well... What a fascinating theory. But how does that relate to the development of laws?”

Andrei was once again seeking Liselotte’s advice at this very moment.

“If the people all claim their rights at once, it may cause conflict across the country. The more trouble there is, the worse public order will be.”

“Yes.”

“The people wouldn’t want that either. That’s why the resolution of such issues needs to be left to the country, for the government to handle.”

“Right...”

“When trouble actually happens, the ones who have to act will be those at the scene of the issue, and whoever conducts the trial. You understand this too, right?”

“I do.”

“But the best-case scenario is for no problems to occur at all. And in order to do that...”

“Our congress has to develop the laws.”

“Yes. The conflict of rights is one of the most important perspectives to have when developing laws for the people. To be more precise, by having this perspective, you’ll be able to envision when those rights will conflict, what situations will cause conflict, and what would be the right judgment to make in response.”

There were some cases where it was better to let the parties involved solve it themselves, and others where it was better for the nation to intervene as soon as it detected the problem. It was the role of laws to be prepared for such situations. Even if an unexpected situation was to occur, a new law could be created to deal with it immediately.

“It is exactly as you say. I see. Looking at it that way indeed relates to law development,” Andrei let out a sound of admiration as he came to understand her point.

“At the same time, the laws of the country need to be established quickly for the same reason. Conflict will happen more frequently in the immediate aftermath of a revolution, when everyone is hyper-aware of their rights. If the laws aren’t ready to handle that, the situation I just described will happen.”

“Haha, how painfully true. Indeed, we’ve been having such a hard time with the basic laws, we’ve neglected to address serious matters such as murder, assault, and theft. Saint Erica said the basic laws will become the backbone of the country, so we’ve been unable to create other laws without them...”

The basic laws that Andrei was referring to here were the equivalent of a country’s constitution in modern Earth society. For the Holy Democratic Republic of Erica, there was nothing more important than the rights of the people. The basic laws were the most substantial way of showing that the country existed for the sake of the people, so the congress members were currently creating them with fervor.

“Yes, that would be correct—the importance of the basic laws should definitely be emphasized. However, I agree with you in that other laws should be prepared concurrently to the basic laws. If a law turns out to be a problem later, you can just revise the basic law.”

Fundamental laws had to establish in abstract terms the ideals of how the country should use its power, how the country existed for the people, how the people were guaranteed their rights and freedoms, and how the country would never infringe upon those rights. They would become the supreme laws of the nation, prioritized above everything else.

However, postponing the creation of other laws to realize the ideals of fundamental laws was pointless if it just made the people’s lives harder in the meantime. It wouldn’t make sense to prioritize one by completely neglecting the other—they both existed for the common purpose of making lives better, after all.

“I see... What matters more is that we, the people, are making the rules. As long as we guarantee that the country exercises its power under the control of the people, we should be able to make other laws before the basic laws.”

“That’s what I believe, yes. Without proper legislation, the people involved in conflicts and those conducting trials will lack clear legal basis for judgments. The matter of whether the country is using its power under the control of the people will be far from their minds. It seems that the congress is making a vote on every issue that arises right now, but...”

They wouldn’t be able to deal with every problem in the country with such a method.

“I understand. I’ll mention it to the congress. However, there are some members who are strongly against the use of laws created by the noble class, and they prefer to examine each law as a congress... Hmm. Is there any good way of preparing the other laws in a speedy fashion?”

“There may be feelings of aversion towards the laws of the monarchy, but they would make the best starting point for discussion. They may not be laws made with the benefit of the people in mind, but there’s much to learn from them. There are also many logical regulations that don’t involve the noble class. If you remove all the exceptions created for the noble class, the old laws of the monarchy should be worth reviewing post-revolution.”

It would require some work to split the laws that benefited nobles from proper regulations, but it would be better than creating new laws from scratch.

“Hmm. Most of the documents on the kingdom’s laws were stored within the destroyed castle. There are some that have been retrieved from noble residences, but there aren’t many.”

“The laws used in minor kingdoms are usually copies of those used in major kingdoms, so you could just ask to see the laws of another nation...”

“We have no ties to other nations in our current state...” Andrei frowned. Even if they wanted to rely on another nation, their neighbors were all subjects of the Proxia Empire. They all feared backlash from the empire, so there was little chance of any of them cooperating.

“In that case, it may be better to ask a jurist, former official, or merchant familiar with the old laws if they possess a copy. If you still can’t find a copy after that, you’ll have to rely on your memory to rewrite them... Jurists tend to have specialized knowledge, so you’d preferably get someone from each area of expertise.”

Each and every line of the law was written with a certain situation in mind. Trying to write new laws from scratch without any understanding was impossible. In order to create them, they needed the assistance of well-educated scholars or officials that used the laws. The next best option after them would be wealthy merchants that traded under a wide range of laws.

However, under the monarchy, only the noble class could become officials and scholars. There were no powerful merchants in a minor nation of this size either.

I doubt there were multiple jurists for every specialty before the revolution, so now that the noble class has been purged by the revolution...

It would probably be extremely difficult to gather the personnel needed. This country was suffering from a severe lack of capable people—that was the impression Liselotte had.

“...” Andrei probably didn’t have anyone in mind either. He frowned and fell silent in thought.

Legislation doesn’t seem to be the only problem they’re having.

Liselotte had only looked around the Holy Democratic Republic of Erica for a few days, but she had noticed a lot in that time. The pride the people had in knowing they had won over the monarchy. The sense of fulfillment they had in knowing that their nation existed for them. The peace of mind and trust they had in knowing that the nation was being represented by their own comrades and not unfamiliar royalty. The vigor of the people living in the city was being supported by such factors. The upper ranks of the country were also overflowing with passion in pursuit of the ideal nation. However...

This country is lacking in everything.

There was no knowledge. No technology. No experience. No resources. No industries other than agriculture. That’s why they couldn’t fully establish the organizations and systems required for the nation to function.

There was no one in their congress that had any familiarity with politics. None of them were from the former noble class; the congress members were all commoners with no connection to politics, coming from origins like farming, construction, shoemaking, smithing, and trading.

While they had gathered a wide range of people from the commoner class, the way they were left to make political decisions on their own was quite concerning. They probably didn’t even understand the state of international politics.

In reality, the current congress was inadequate for developing laws, and the administration was in danger of becoming completely dysfunctional because of it. The constant postponement of individual legislation and any specific definitions also amplified the issue.

Because of that, the state of the country’s authority was vague and unclear. As Liselotte had described, the congress currently met for every decision that had to be made, and the nation had too many problems to solve in such a way.

After all their efforts in creating a government with a congress for legislation, a nominated leader of the state, and a democratic control of the authority...

They’re being shaken by the system. I observed one of their congress meetings, and the members seem to find enjoyment in arguing over things, like they’re drunk on it...

They were failing to use that system. In particular, the main legislative body—the congress—was the root of democracy. The reason why the legislative and executive power that the monarchy held was split into the new system was so that executive power could be democratically controlled through a congress.

If there was no democratic control over the congress as an administrative body, they would be able to use their power just like the previous monarchy.

If they don’t solve those issues first, this country will fall apart in the very near future...

Frankly speaking, the Holy Democratic Republic of Erica was only successfully established because the nation was small, their activities were limited, and they had nothing of interest to foreign nations.

Because of that, they were barely managing to exist as a country—and were simply lucky. If a foreign nation were to attack now, the Holy Democratic Republic of Erica would not be able to win. It was hard to tell how they had even succeeded in the revolution, actually.

Perhaps Saint Erica wasn’t being given enough credit in that sense. The military strength of the Holy Democratic Republic of Erica changed greatly depending on her existence. That was Liselotte’s analysis, which was greatly influenced by seeing the ruins of the destroyed castle.

The effect Saint Erica had on the morale of the people was immense as well. It was because of her that the revolution happened, and succeeded.

However, for better or for worse, Saint Erica’s existence had influenced this country too much. The people may have gone along with the revolution, but the one who made it succeed was Saint Erica alone.

The power of the Divine Arms won the revolution, establishing the country at a rapid speed.

Could the issues in this country be caused by the omission of most of the processes of a revolution? They’ve experienced consecutive successes, which is why the people are so confident in themselves...

Erica had supposedly traveled the country to start the revolution, preaching before the public in every region governed by nobility.

In doing so, she’d planted the image of authority figures as evil in the minds of the people, then executed them. This had roused the people of those regions, and by doing so, she’d skipped decades’ worth of how the process would happen on Earth. Instead of ten to one hundred years of wealthy intellectuals sharing their knowledge and awareness of human rights, Erica had planted those thoughts straight into the heads of the people through a clear reality.

Then, after putting together a makeshift democracy system and being appointed as the first representative of the nation, the saint goes off on a journey? What is she trying to accomplish? It looks like she’s just trying to start a war with every person of royal and noble blood she can.

She should have known that abducting Liselotte would result in a serious international issue with the Galarc Kingdom. Yet, that was exactly what she did.

It was hard to imagine that she wanted to make an enemy of every kingdom and empire in Strahl, yet her actions were indiscriminate enough to imply exactly that. Even she should know that starting needless wars would just result in the deaths of the weak she was trying to save...

I don’t get it. Is Erica’s goal really to bring salvation to the weak? She said she was creating a country for the people, by the people, in order to save the weak, but...

Liselotte could only see the saint as a dangerous person. Well, there was no doubt she was dangerous to begin with, but her methods of accomplishing her goals were fatally flawed.

At the same time, she gave these people permission to interact with me while she was away, revealing the weakness of this country directly to me...

Liselotte had been lost deep in her thoughts until now, but she suddenly looked up and realized Andrei was looking at her with a heated gaze.

“Umm... Is something the matter?”

“No, I was just thinking about why Saint Erica brought you to our country. She truly understands what our country needs the most—that is to say, people like you.”

“O-Oh. Is that so...” Liselotte murmured awkwardly.

“Liselotte, I need you.” Andrei suddenly uttered what sounded like a courtship line.

“I’ve already rejected that offer many times already.” Liselotte shook her head with a sigh. Indeed, she had experienced this conversation with Andrei multiple times since he began frequenting her room.

“But you’re needed here!” Andrei didn’t back down and protested firmly.

“I’m afraid I cannot help.”

Knowing he would only get more persistent from here, Liselotte stated her thoughts gently but clearly. Andrei was easily swayed by his emotions, so she knew he wasn’t the type to understand with just a gentle answer.

“Mr. Andrei, your words are turning into a confession of love again,” Natalia, the girl accompanying them as a guard, commented with a grin. She didn’t care for the political talk, nearly dozing off in her chair in the corner of the room, but the change in topic had brought her back to attention.

“Oh, no! That isn’t my intention...” Andrei blushed, reacting like an innocent young man.

“Hmm, is that so?” Natalia continued to grin wickedly.

“Wh-What’s that look for, Natalia?”

“Oh, nothing... Come to think of it, I heard a rumor yesterday. The straitlaced Saint Erica devotee, Mr. Andrei, is spending every day with a young and beautiful unmarried woman... Perhaps spring has finally come for him?”

“I-I’m not...! I’m purely after Liselotte’s cooperation for the sake of our country!” Andrei denied in shock.

“Oh? I didn’t say anything about the woman being Liselotte, did I? In fact, I spend all day guarding you too, don’t I?” Natalia was one step ahead of him.

“N-Natalia...! I-I’m so sorry about this, Liselotte.”

“Ahaha. It’s fine...” Liselotte glossed over things with a sociable smile.

Andrei wasn’t a bad person. His intense belief in Saint Erica blinded him at times, but he had a good personality at heart. Many people would find him an honest and hardworking man. He was still lacking experience as a politician, but he was very willing to learn, and absorbed the information he was given rapidly.

However, Liselotte was abducted and brought here against her will. She hadn’t forgotten that—and she wasn’t about to cooperate with the Holy Democratic Republic of Erica just because the upper ranks and its citizens weren’t bad people.

As a noble of the Galarc Kingdom, Liselotte had a duty to gather information about this country. That’s why she cooperated to a level where the other side would lower their guard and trust her enough to give her beneficial information. In order to do that, she gave them some useful advice, but it wouldn’t amount to much with their overwhelming lack of personnel...

In reality, she seemed to have gained quite a lot of trust from the two of them in these last several days. For example, Andrei’s guard, Natalia, who was a former adventurer. After listening to their conversations every day, she started to relax, even cutting in to put a stop to Andrei’s ranting at times. She was nineteen years old, and while she had acted rather crabbily towards Liselotte for being a noblewoman in the beginning, her personality was actually rather friendly.

But I shouldn’t get too close to her. These people are from a potential enemy nation. I cannot empathize with them too much.

Winning the other side’s trust while keeping her own intentions at a distance was something Liselotte had to do, naturally, as a noblewoman and merchant. And the other side was trying to do the same to her. Despite that, she felt like she was deceiving them. When she considered the future turbulence awaiting the Holy Democratic Republic of Erica, she couldn’t help but feel ashamed.

Perhaps it was because she knew that even if she pointed out the issues that would soon arise, no easy solution existed for them.

Or perhaps she had learned too much about these two. They were too honest to deal with a merchant like Liselotte.

If they had met somewhere else, they may have become friends with her like Haruto and Miharu were. Perhaps it was because she had started thinking of these two in the same way.

How would this country look to Haruto’s eyes, as someone who was also reborn into this world?

Suddenly, that question popped into Liselotte’s mind. She didn’t consider her own opinions to be absolute, and it was possible the impression she received of this country was off the mark. She wondered what Rio would think, as someone born in this world with the memories of growing up in another democratic world.

Sir Haruto, huh...

At the thought of Rio, a somewhat saddened, somewhat uneasy, conflicted look appeared on Liselotte’s face as she watched the exchange between Natalia and Andrei.

“E-Enough teasing, Natalia. Liselotte is a noblewoman, so I’m sure she has a much more worthy fiancé than me,” Andrei said suddenly, bringing up the topic in order to hide his embarrassment. But by doing so, he had touched upon a rather delicate topic. If Liselotte answered that she did have a fiancé, things would only get awkward for Andrei and Natalia, who were keeping her captive.

“Well, I suppose that makes sense... Do you?” Natalia asked nervously.

“No, I don’t have a fiancé.” Liselotte shook her head with a forced smile.

“Hmm. What about a crush?”

“I don’t...really...” She faltered, unable to deny it immediately. There was someone who immediately came to mind, but she wasn’t sure whether her feelings were romantic or not.

Ah, it looks like she does. Natalia’s instincts immediately tipped her off.

“Ahem... Anyways, it truly is difficult, isn’t it? The task of creating a country for the people, by the people. Wouldn’t you agree, Liselotte?” It seemed like such romance talk was still too early for Andrei, who cleared his throat and changed the topic in embarrassment.

“That’s only to be expected... If the ways of the monarchy were wrong, then the new nation has to show the people what the right way is. That burden falls upon you and the other politicians,” Liselotte responded with a slightly saddened smile, thinking about someone who wasn’t there at the moment.

“It’s truly a big responsibility. I hope Saint Erica returns soon—she should be expected back around this time, but...” Feeling the weight of the nation on his shoulders, Andrei smiled wryly. Erica would return to the country the next day.

◇ ◇ ◇

The next afternoon, First Head of State Erica of the Holy Democratic Republic of Erica returned.

“Oh, how long it has been. We have missed you so much, Saint Erica! Thank goodness you have returned safely...”

As the prime minister, Andrei worked in the same official residence as Erica. As soon as he heard Erica had returned, he hurried to her office, rejoicing over her return from the bottom of his heart as she remained seated in her chair.

“It’s good to see you full of energy, Andrei. I’m also glad to be back. Did anything major happen while I was gone?” Erica smiled brightly as she sought an update on the recent state of things.

“Let’s see... There were no major problems. The city repairs are ongoing, and the people are in high spirits. The congress is also actively discussing how to bring a better future to the people.”

“Why, that sounds lovely. I knew I could count on you, Andrei,” Erica immediately said in praise.

“N-Not at all. Everyone did their best to protect the country while you were away. It was nothing of my own doing.”

“You did your best too, no? That was what came to my mind the moment you stepped into the room. Ah, what a good expression, I thought.”

“R-Really? Such words are wasted on me.” Andrei bowed his head shyly.

“It may be a bit late to say this, but I left this country because I wanted you and the other congress members to gain experience. Of course, I had no doubt everyone would be able to handle it, but hearing your words just now made me very pleased.”

“You thought that far into it...”

“Hehe.” Erica grinned at Andrei’s emotional reaction.

“O-Oh, that’s right. Speaking of changes, Liselotte is truly a wonderful person. As expected of Saint Erica to see promise in her.” Andrei’s voice was high-pitched with embarrassment as he spoke about Liselotte.

“Right? She’s a bright and clever girl. Despite being the daughter of a leading noble, she thinks of the people and governs them well.”

“Yes, I was surprised by the depth of her views. I had more to learn from her than the other way around.”

“The Holy Democratic Republic of Erica needs more people like her right now.”

“Yes. I keenly felt our shortage of personnel by talking to her. That’s why we must bring her into our country. That’s what you intended, right?”

“Andrei...” Erica didn’t speak any words of confirmation or denial, instead calling Andrei’s name as though she was touched.

“She can definitely be swayed. I’m sure she will agree with our thoughts soon.”

“What does she think about how she was restrained and forcefully brought to this country?”

“As per the orders Natalia and the others received, I told her the first time I showed her around the capital that there was a slight misunderstanding, and to wait until you returned to discuss the details. She hasn’t brought up the topic since then... But unfortunately, I don’t think she feels very happy about it.” Andrei frowned a little. Ever since he’d started frequenting Liselotte’s room, he’d started to understand her nature more. She was born as a high-ranked noble, yet she interacted with commoners like them on equal standing.

If such a person was so enraged, perhaps there was validity behind her reasoning? Andrei continued following Erica’s orders out of his near-religious devotion to her, but he was beginning to wonder if he should lend an ear to Liselotte’s reasoning as well.

“I see... I’ve given you a difficult role to bear, Andrei. Forgive me.” Erica saw through the subtleties in Andrei’s expression and apologized with a bitter smile.

“N-No, not at all. It is my duty as prime minister to support you, Saint Erica. I know that this is expected of someone in a political position.” Andrei shook his head humbly.

“You really are an earnest worker. But I sometimes worry you’re holding in all your emotions.”

“I am unworthy of such consideration.”

“...” Erica stared with a loving gaze at Andrei as he humbled himself, then suddenly stood up. She walked up to him and stroked his cheek gently.

“Uh... S-Saint Erica?” Andrei froze.

“If anything is bothering you, tell me all about it.” She giggled.

“R-Right! Gladly!” Andrei nodded enthusiastically.

“Now, it’s time to pay Liselotte a visit. Andrei, gather all the congress members that are available right now. As soon as they’re ready, bring Liselotte to the congress office.”

“I understand.” Andrei nodded readily, then hurried out of the room with brisk footsteps.

◇ ◇ ◇

An hour later, Liselotte was shown out of the room she was confined in by Natalia, who led her to the meeting room. Waiting inside the office were Erica, Andrei, and dozens of other congress members from the Holy Democratic Republic of Erica.

Liselotte hadn’t heard that Erica had returned, so she walked in assuming she was observing another congress meeting. When she spotted Erica standing on the platform, her eyes widened. Natalia nudged her to stand before the platform.

“Hello, Liselotte.”

It wasn’t Sakuraba Erika who greeted her, but the saint. She had a sociable attitude, as though she had never attacked Liselotte in Amande.

“...” Liselotte didn’t respond. She furrowed her brows in a glare, expressing her anger. Even the normally good-natured Liselotte could be enraged.

That was how awful this saint had been to her.

She had behaved maturely before Andrei and Natalia because there was no point in being hostile to them, but she didn’t have to hold back before Erica.

“Oh my, dear Liselotte. You’ll get wrinkles like that. It’d be a waste of such a cute face, wouldn’t you say?”

Liselotte’s expression wasn’t severe enough to form wrinkles, but Erica feigned ignorance and pointed it out anyway. The congress room wasn’t that big, so her voice carried clearly even at a normal speaking volume.

“I’m still fifteen years old, so I don’t need your concern.”

“Oh, really? You don’t look fifteen at all...” Considering her knowledge of Liselotte’s previous life as Rikka, she was probably being sarcastic.

“I couldn’t recognize you either, Ms. Sakuraba. The last time I saw you in Amande, you had the face of a savage beast.”

Liselotte returned the favor by purposefully calling Erica by her last name. Andrei and Natalia, who were standing behind Erica, cocked their heads in confusion, unaware of Erica’s last name.

“Oh my, what are you talking about?” Erica maintained her feigned ignorance.

“Are you suffering from memory loss?”

“I truly don’t remember. It’s been a long and eventful journey, so the trifling matters that occur along the way get forgotten...”

“Trifling matters, you say? I see, your exhausting duties must have accelerated your aging. Do take care of your health.” Liselotte looked at Erica’s face as though she were genuinely concerned.

“Why, thank you for your concern. Hahaha.”

Erica and Liselotte smiled gently while throwing knife-sharp words at each other. Andrei, Natalia, and the others in the room watched their exchange in silence.

“Natalia, does the air feel rather hostile to you...?”

“It’s not just the air that’s hostile right now. An intelligent woman is speaking sarcastically with a smile—you better carve this moment into your intuition.”

Standing behind Erica, Andrei sensed the serious atmosphere in the room and turned to question Natalia about it. Natalia answered in a cold sweat.

“Now then, could you explain this situation and why I was kidnapped to the Holy Democratic Republic of Erica? I, Liselotte Cretia of the Galarc Kingdom, demand to be returned immediately.”

She had waited long enough for Erica’s return. With no patience left for mind games, Liselotte stated her position clearly.

“Unfortunately, you cannot be returned to the Galarc Kingdom. You have learned of our national secret.”

“That you are a hero, you mean?”

“That’s right,” Erica agreed without hesitation.

“You sure admitted it easily for a national secret. Not even Prime Minister Andrei knew the truth.” Liselotte looked at Andrei.

“Is that true, Saint Erica?” Andrei asked with a hopeful look.

“Now that it’s out in the open, I can only accept it. It’s true, Andrei. I am apparently a hero,” Erica answered. The room buzzed with noise.

“Quiet, everyone. Let me speak to Liselotte,” Erica said.

“If you’re willing to admit it that easily, then I don’t believe there was a need to kidnap me. Are you saying you wouldn’t have abducted me if I hadn’t asked if you were the hero in Amande?”

“There’s no point in discussing hypotheticals. You learned of an important secret, so I simply thought to bring a souvenir of my own back with me.”

“Is the fact that you’re the hero an important secret?”

“Someone as bright as you should know the value of information. Haven’t you come to a conclusion for that reason already?”

“Only that you can use it to your advantage by keeping it a secret until the right moment. But I want to hear the answer from you, considering all the trouble I’ve gone through because of it.”

“That I cannot do. I won’t be giving you answers.” Erica declined answering with a bright grin.

“Is it related to how you’re a prophet as well? The prophecy you saw should have appeared in your dreams shortly after the hero summoning, but...” Liselotte used key words that would draw out a reaction and watched Erica’s face for more information.

“Oh, you seem rather knowledgeable about it.”

“I’ve met the other five heroes before. As far as I know, they were taught how to use their Divine Arms in their dreams.”

“Yes, that would be correct. I saw that dream shortly after I was summoned as well.”

“...” Liselotte stared at the way Erica readily nodded.

“What is it?” Erica looked puzzled.

“Was the prophecy from that dream?”

“Who knows? If you join our country, perhaps I could share that information with you...”

“I see. No thank you, then.” Liselotte backed down immediately.

“What a shame. Ah, speaking of heroes, I met the hero girl from Galarc. She had a determined spirit. There was another quiet Japanese girl with her, but was she a hero as well? I believe her name was Miharu,” Erica said, as though it suddenly came to her mind.

Miharu was there...? Does that mean Sir Haruto was present as well?

Liselotte’s eyes widened faintly, wondering if he had returned from his trip.

“But there was a gray-haired boy who seemed stronger than her there. Could he be the hero instead? His physical body enhancement was on par with mine.”

It turned out Erica had met with someone resembling Haruto.

“Who knows? If information about the heroes is a national secret as you say, then I cannot answer. I don’t want to indiscriminately spread personal information about others either.”

“Hmph. You say that, but you forced my information out of me.” Erica puffed up her cheeks, sulking.

“Forced? That’s a bit misleading. We both agreed to answer each other’s questions, and I followed those rules too.”

“What about all the questions I know you must have asked Andrei while I was away? You say you don’t want to spread personal information, but you’re fine with prying into other people’s lives? Isn’t that a bit unfair? But I guess that’s the typical way of the noble class.”

“Indiscriminately, I said. It depends on who I’m talking to, and what about. A matter of trust. And you were the one who ordered Andrei to teach me about the Holy Democratic Republic of Erica yourself, no? It’s absurd to expect the head of state not to come up in such discussions.”

“You have such an eloquent way with words. And a dauntless attitude. It’s why you don’t appear fifteen, but it’s also the type of personality highly sought after from politicians. Everyone should learn from you.” Erica giggled in amusement, addressing the room at large.

“Haha...”

Andrei and Natalia had strained smiles behind Erica. Liselotte had never shown her noble attitude in front of the two of them.

Part of the reason was because Andrei had said to her at their first meeting that he wouldn’t make any political decisions as a proxy for Erica, but Liselotte had also wanted to imply that she never saw him as a politician.

“That aside, the gray-haired boy. Could he be in that kind of relationship with you?”

“You sure change the subject quickly. I doubt it’s an appropriate topic for a place like this, but what kind of relationship do you mean?” Liselotte looked exasperated at the sudden change in topic.

“Hmm... I wouldn’t call you lovers, but you said you were interested in someone, no? I was just wondering if he could be that person. He seemed to be surrounded by many lovely women who adored him,” Erica said teasingly, but Liselotte’s response was blunt.

“I have no reason to answer you.”

“If you refuse to answer every one of my questions, I won’t answer any of yours. I’m sure you have lots to ask me as well.”

“I don’t mind if you’re selective over your answers, so please ask something more worthwhile. And I’ve never believed in all your words to begin with.”

“It seems I really am hated after all,” Erica said, expressing a disappointed mood that the whole room could pick up on.

“I understand. Then let’s get to the point—though I’m not sure what to discuss first. If there’s anything you wish to ask, feel free to ask it,” Erica said in compromise, making a display of how generous she was.

She sure excels at making herself look good...

By doing something that showed the difference between herself and the other party, she could bring down their image. It was a cunning but clever trick. The side being insulted would not be amused and would be more prone to snapping; it was clear that Erica was used to inciting others. However, Liselotte wasn’t so easily provoked into becoming angry.

“If you met the three of them, does that mean you went to the Galarc Castle?” If Erica was willing to give answers, then she wouldn’t hold back her questions.

“Yes, I figured I had to address the matter of your abduction. I spoke to the Galarc King as well.”

“With His Majesty...?”

“The Galarc Kingdom is no good. I warned them to abandon the monarchy, but the evil king is obsessed with his power. He wouldn’t heed my words at all and threatened me with his military power instead,” Erica sighed sadly.

“That doesn’t sound like the king that I know,” Liselotte said, indirectly suggesting Erica was lying.

“But that is the impression I received from him.”

“...”

“Oh yes, your strong attendant was also there.”

“I see. So Aria’s safe.” Liselotte had been abducted immediately after Erica sent a powerful attack at Aria, kicking up a cloud of dust and blocking her view, so she hadn’t been able to see what happened. Knowing that Aria was still alive was enough to fill her with relief.

“She seemed very lively and ready to attack me at any moment. Perhaps our different impressions of the king are caused by her making a misleading testimony? She seemed to be extremely hostile towards me.”

“That’s only to be expected after what you did in Amande. But Aria would never give a testimony that twisted the truth,” Liselotte stated clearly.

“You seem to trust her a lot. Just like how I trust the people of this country, including the people here right now.” Erica turned her head slightly, looking at the people gathered in the room with a gentle smile. Everyone beamed back at her happily.

“Aria and I have gone through a lot together. Enough to form a foundation of trust.”

It was hard to imagine Erica had any trust accumulated—if anything, she seemed like the type to discard the subjects of her human relationships after gaining their trust. There was nothing to believe about a person like that who looked down on Aria. That’s what Liselotte was implying with her words.

“I see, so you treasure those experiences. That must be what we’re lacking with you. We’d like you to join us at this very moment, but it seems impossible to ask you to trust and assist us without those experiences,” Erica said.

“Naturally.”

Yes, that was a given. That was the last thing Liselotte wanted to hear from her, but she kept her sarcasm limited to a single word of agreement.

“Andrei and Natalia have been very good to you, no? They truly believe in making a country for the sake of the people. Shouldn’t you have accumulated some experiences with them while I was gone?”

“Yes, I suppose... More than with you, at least.”

Liselotte glanced at Andrei and Natalia and nodded.

“In that case, why don’t you speak your mind in front of the two of them?”

“Do you wish for me to repeat what I said in Amande here? No matter how many times you ask, my answer won’t change. And I’ve discussed many things with Andrei during your absence.”

“Even then, I want you to express yourself in front of everyone here. As the daughter of a great lord, born and raised in a major kingdom, please tell us how you see the rule of the monarchy. As a member of the noble class with actually respectable values, what is your perspective? I’ve received a brief report on what was discussed while waiting in this room, and it seems like you gave a lot of advice on our administration system. Thank you for that.”

“I didn’t say anything of that much importance.”

“Not at all. I found the topic of the conflict in rights a very fascinating topic. It is a problem sure to arise between the people in the future of this country, one which will strongly influence how our administration system can bloom as a democracy. That’s why I’d like to hold a discussion over that topic today,” Erica said, leading the meeting with the aura of a teacher.

She said she was a lecturer at a university, if I recall. No wonder she seems so familiar with this kind of thing... Liselotte recalled what she’d heard from her in Amande.

“I’m fine with that, but may I ask one thing first?” she asked, adding a condition before participating in Erica’s discussion.

“Yes?”

“Judging by the way you’re leading the discussion, I believe you must have realized the latent issues this country is carrying already.”

Liselotte asked to confirm if Erica was already aware of the problems—and had left them alone knowingly.

“Hehehe. How observant of you. Indeed, I’ve noticed what the direction this country is heading towards is and what issues will arise already.”

“R-Really?! Why didn’t you...” Andrei looked shocked behind her. The congress members in the room stirred quietly.

“It’s easy for me to order you to make countermeasures, but I cannot be giving you orders for everything. I want everyone to gain experience, not knowledge. You already have unconditional belief in everything I say. Merely following orders isn’t enough for you to grow.” Erica turned around and smiled gracefully at Andrei, then looked around at the faces of the congress members.

“You truly predicted everything,” he murmured.

“Is that why you made them show me the country in your absence? So that I could see through the issues and tell them to Andrei? Since your people are less likely to believe me as an outsider.”

“Hehe. You truly have superb observational skills. I was sure you would notice this country’s problems. Whether you would actually pass them on to Andrei or not was a fifty-fifty chance in my mind, though.”

“...” Liselotte found Erica’s gloating smile rather unpleasant and eerie. She couldn’t tell at what point Erica had had everything planned, how far her plan extended, or why she would do such a thing.

Although she stated her various intentions, Liselotte couldn’t help but feel like those statements were misleading as well. However, she had no proof. Erica hid everything too well.

“If you’re done with your question, let’s move on to the main discussion. For some time now, I have been preaching to the people of the flaws of human governance. Human rulers make laws convenient for themselves, and those laws change every time the ruler changes. It’s a highly unstable system.”

“Is that why you want to create a society where the laws rule over people equally? So that people can be judged as equals.”

“As expected of you. You understand that what I want is universal laws to bring justice and salvation to the weak, don’t you? That’s why humans cannot create the rules. They’re different things. Humans cannot create laws of a higher order than other humans, so those laws are not absolute. For example, it would be out of the question to accept a law that approves of the noble class and social status system. It’s a bit of a simplification, but that’s the gist of it...”

In Earth terms, this way of thinking was called the rule of law. It was originally a principle developed from the foundations of Anglo-American law, but they were currently in a world with vastly different cultural foundations. It was hard to say if such ideas would have ever budded here of their own accord. As an aside, there was a similarly named rule of law in this world with different principles that was developed as a continental law.

If the rule of law from modern Earth was to spread in this world—for example, if Japan’s constitution were to be applied here—the privileges of the current royalty and nobility would immediately become negated. Either their statuses would be entirely abolished, or they would remain in name with no real privileges left.

However, forcefully spreading that idea would inevitably result in fierce rebellion from royalty and nobles unwilling to part with their vested interests.

“Don’t you think it’s a wonderful way of thinking?” Erica turned to question Liselotte, who was seated across from her, with a cheerful expression. Liselotte knew she was being tested as a member of the noble class.

“I believe I said something similar in Amande, but it’s unjust for the noble class to oppress the lower class without reason, and humans have no right to discriminate. This is my personal opinion,” she replied firmly.

“You truly have splendid values. If all royals and nobles were like you, the world would have remained a kind place to live in for a long time. However, not everyone thinks like you. Humans are foolish creatures. There are those who want to discriminate. Those who feel a sense of superiority and relief by looking down on others. As long as those types of people exist in this world, the weak will always be subject to the whims of those in control. Everyone here has experienced this firsthand.”

In response to Erica’s statement, the congress members all spoke up in agreement.

Before anyone knew it, the atmosphere of the room had turned Erica into the representative of the people, and Liselotte into the representative of all royals and nobles.

This was no discussion.

It was a trial. Everyone in the room besides Liselotte had experienced hardship in their lives because of the noble class, and they all agreed with Erica’s thoughts.

Liselotte had had a faint idea of what would happen from the moment she stepped into the room and saw Erica’s face, but she also knew the moment she abandoned the discussion, she would be fully recognized as the villain. She knew she had no chance of winning, but she had no choice but to justify herself through the discussion.

“I believe I can understand the reason why everyone finds you and your ideas so wonderful, Saint Erica,” she said, looking around the room.

“What about yourself, Liselotte? Do you not agree that my ideas are wonderful?”

“On a personal level, I can empathize with them to a great extent.”

“What a noble-like response. You won’t agree that they’re wonderful. It almost sounds like you harbor ill feelings about it...”

“I merely thought that guided yes or no questions wouldn’t be enough to express my thoughts.”

“And as a result, I sensed there were ill feelings in your response. What’s wrong with that? Do you disagree with the idea of guiding people to the correct path through a higher-order law, a truth of the world that realizes the justice of bringing salvation to the weak?”

“It’s not wrong... I just think that rapidly promoting such an idea can result in chaos.”

“Oh? How so?”

“You’ll be making an enemy of every noble who wants to maintain their interests. Such a thing will result in war.”

“The noble class are the ones in the wrong, no? If the noble class won’t resolve the injustice themselves, then the oppressed people must rise in revolution to correct them...”

“It’s not only figures of power who live in a kingdom. There are many people in a country, and it’s because of those people that the country can flourish. I understand that if the people wish for correction, then a revolution is inevitable and justified. However, forcing a revolution when the system of the kingdom is solid and stable could result in a tragedy.”

“Are you that afraid of confronting other nobles?” Erica taunted.

“I am afraid. For example, let’s say I led the people of Amande in a revolution against the kingdom. All the nobles of the nation would direct their military forces at me in retaliation. But would I be the only one at risk? Won’t the people living in my territory get killed along the way? How do you think the people would see such a situation? I’d be criticized for starting a pointless war with no chance of victory,” Liselotte said without hesitation.

“So you’re telling me to wait until the passing of time wears down the governing system of the noble class? That I should ignore the people out there suffering right this moment?”

“I don’t want those people to be ignored... But having a just reason doesn’t make it okay to put them on a sinking ship.”

Liselotte frowned bitterly. First and foremost, the questions Erica was demanding answers for weren’t matters an individual could resolve alone. They were difficult problems that a forced solution could ruin any hope of solving, dragging others into the destruction.

“So you’d abandon the resolution of the problem. In that case, you should discard your noble status. If you won’t do that, it means you want to selfishly cling to your status in order to continue living comfortably as a noble. You think that if you say words to pander to the people, you won’t be hated by them,” Erica said, pointing at Liselotte and criticizing her. It was a terrible way of one-sidedly labeling her.

However, most of the congress members present sided with Erica, who stood on the side of the victims—the people. Many voices echoed in agreement, criticizing Liselotte, who stood on the side of the perpetrators.

They believed that if she truly thought of the people, she would be willing to throw away her status that allowed her a comfortable life.

“I am a noble of the Galarc Kingdom. As the governor of Amande, I have to be responsible for the people living there. If I abandon that position, the lives of the people in Amande will become unstable. Wouldn’t that be irresponsible?”

In the end, Liselotte didn’t state that she would discard her noble status. While her expression stiffened involuntarily, she stated her opinion without fear. In response, the participating congress members expressed their disappointment and rage. Some voices shouted, “Don’t make excuses!” and others echoed them in agreement. They had no idea how much Liselotte was adored by the people of Amande.

“I know that Amande is a wonderful city. Indeed, without you, the lives of the people there would be of a much lesser quality.” Contrary to everyone’s expectations, Erica readily praised Liselotte’s governing of Amande.

“In that case, please send me back to Amande. I cannot fulfill my duty as governor in my present location. By abducting me from my kingdom, you have made the lives of the people of Amande unstable. Am I wrong?”

“Indeed, that could be one way of looking at it. But how about seeing it this way? The reason why Amande has been governed well until now is because Liselotte Cretia is a good noble. But what if the next noble that governs Amande is a tyrant? There must be many who live in fear of that.”

“That’s exactly why you should send me back immediately...”

“Don’t you think that you should take measures to ensure that the people of Amande can live safely, even without the presence of Liselotte Cretia? So that the people won’t be endangered no matter who takes over Amande after you.”

“What are you trying to say?”

Liselotte seemed to have sensed something from that response, as she asked her question with a fed-up look.

“In other words, despite your claims of responsibility over the people of Amande, you haven’t been fulfilling that duty. You may be doing well in the present, but you haven’t given any thought to the next generations. It’s the same as disregarding the entire future of the city. Would anyone here wish to live under such a governor?” Erica said, inviting the listening congress members to respond.

“No!”

“A leader has to think about the future!”

“That’s right, that’s right!” they said, one after another.

We’re going around in circles. This saint is saying to make the city democratic so that the people’s lives won’t sink into depravity. Even though she knows that doing so will make an enemy of every royal and noble in the kingdom, contradicting her own point. But even if I explain that, no one here will listen.

The rules that Liselotte could set for Amande were ranked below the higher-order national laws and territory laws. Thus, as a governor, there was no point in making rules that went against the national and territory laws. On top of that, it was possible for new governors to repeal the rules set by previous governors.

Even if a new system was introduced to keep the rule ongoing after a change in governor, it would require special permission from the territory lord and king, and even that permission could be reversed if a new lord and king came into power. In which case, it would ultimately require a revolution to rebuild society and implement the rule of law.

This is probably as far as Saint Erica wants this discussion to go.

Since she wasn’t able to shift the destination of their talk, it was Liselotte’s defeat. She knew she had a slim chance of victory to begin with, and that was exactly what happened.

Now that things had come to this, there was no point in repeating herself in this discussion. The only thing to do was to move on to the next stage herself.

“I believe we’ve drifted rather far from the main point of the discussion. Is that okay? I recall the topic to be about the conflict of rights and how to make democracy succeed in this country, but the conversation was mostly similar to what we exchanged in Amande,” Liselotte asked Erica with a shrug.

There were voices who opposed this. Shouts of “Don’t change the topic,” “You’re running away,” and “Accept your defeat graciously” sounded out, but Liselotte didn’t appear bothered by them.

“I believe we’ve given the topic plenty of debate. Today, our respective rights to freedom of speech were presented to each other. We put into practice the collision of rights.”

“That just sounds like sophistry...”

“No, the biggest difference from our conversation in Amande is the members of congress gathered here to decide on this country’s future. That, and I believe our discussion was only of such a high degree because it was made by you and me. If either one of us had been replaced by someone else, the talk wouldn’t have gotten this heated. There’s great meaning in allowing those here today to hear this conversation. Their thoughts after hearing the discussion will surely influence the future of this country that they will create. I am certain of this.” Erica looked around the room with a derisive sneer.

“Well then, may I assume you’ve achieved your goal in calling me here?”

“No, there’s one last thing... Liselotte. Will you lend me your strength? Let us bring salvation to the weak together. If you and I join hands, our peaceful reign will last far longer than that in Amande.”

“That sounds like a rather dangerous statement. Are you telling me to betray my country?” Liselotte frowned. Erica’s statement just now sounded like she was planning a revolution in Galarc, and wanted assistance.

“How you interpret it is up to you. But as a hero, I can make it happen. I’m capable of it. That’s why I’m making this proposal.”

“There are five other heroes, you know? They’ve all been confirmed to be affiliated with a kingdom. Do you plan on making enemies of all five of them?”

“That won’t be a problem. I won’t lose to any hero that’s been living a warm and sheltered life provided by their country. As long as I stand on the front line as the Saint and a hero, the people will not know defeat.”

“That’s quite the confidence you have...”

“Yes. That is why I am requesting your assistance once again. You understand it perfectly well, don’t you? That humans are foolish creatures. That is why we need intelligent people like you. Let’s create our reality together.” Erica smiled gently, offering her hand to Liselotte.

“I’ve never particularly thought of myself as smart. People can’t be valued by their intelligence. Your so-called ideal government system doesn’t measure people like that either, does it? That’s why you consider people to be born equal.” Liselotte did not accept Erica’s hand.

“Yes, exactly.”

“In that case, please stop this extortion. How does forcing me to obey you like this make you any different from the evil noble class that you detest so much?”

Likes, dislikes. People were free to express their opinions. They had the freedom to convey their thoughts to others. However, it was wrong to force those thoughts on someone else. People had the freedom not to be forced into things, after all.

When the conflict of rights happened without any respect for each other, imposition occurred. The act of forcing another into something was coercion. And when coercion went too far, it became controlling.

Of course, merely discussing one’s opinions and ideas was fine, as it was the very essence of democracy. However, trying to bend the opinions and thoughts of someone you disagreed with, controlling them no matter what—that was the equivalent of a human ruling over another human. Wasn’t that essentially the same abuse of power that they hated so much?

Liselotte stared at Erica in protest.

“Wh-What did she just say?!”

“How does insisting on the right thing make us the same as the noble class?!”

“We only act as a collective will! The consensus of the people is what is correct!”

“What slander!”

“Take back your words!”

“Wicked noblewoman who only cares for her own interests without fulfilling her duties!”

“She only cares about herself! That’s why she won’t discard her status!”

“A woman born in a blessed environment wouldn’t understand us!”

“All she does is take taxes from the people she should be protecting! This woman is a criminal!”

“She only knows how to ride her high horse! Repent!”

“This woman is a witch!”

“Convict her! She must be convicted by us!”

The congress members reddened in anger and yelled abusively at Liselotte unanimously. They tried to guilt her by calling her evil, to teach her the truth. They must have felt personally attacked by her point, as their reactions were excessively heated.

“...” Liselotte bit her lip sadly, but didn’t argue back.

“Guh...” Her body was knocked down, and she slammed heavily into the ground. She was unable to make a safe landing and bounced fiercely, rolling across it. Aria landed after her lightly.

Meanwhile, Rio fell down beside Aishia and swung his wind-clad sword, slashing away the orbs of light raining on her.

Aria... Sir Haruto! Liselotte looked between the two of them, overcome with emotion.

Aishia. Another change of plan. Aria and I will take over here. You fly out of the city like this. Don’t worry about the long-ranged shots. I’ll block them all.

As soon as Rio sent that message, he created dozens of orbs of light himself. They were less than ten centimeters in diameter, and there were just enough of them not to block his vision.

Okay. Aishia nodded, then accelerated towards the perimeter of the city.

“D-Don’t let them get away! Go! Go after them! Someone, assist Saint Erica!” Andrei, who had been dazed by the series of events unfolding, snapped back to his senses and gave the nearby guards orders.

“It’s fine. I won’t be defeated by something like this.” Erica slowly got to her feet, then raised her voice to declare her safety. She brushed the dirt off her clothes in annoyance, seemingly having taken no damage at all.

“Saint Erica!”

“Oh, Saint Erica!” Those watching on spoke in awe. Erica lifted her staff as though to respond to them.

She was slammed into the ground with that much force and got up without a scratch. She’s as tough as Aria described her... Rio observed Erica below him and swallowed.

“I was wondering who was causing this commotion, but I see now. And the boy above you is the one from the Galarc Castle. So you followed me?” Erica looked between Aria standing before her and Rio floating above her, then sighed tiredly.

“Leave the saint to me!” Aria yelled at Rio. Part of her intention was probably to have Rio stand on watch with his abilities to cover the sky and ground, but she must have had her own emotions towards Erica after what happened in Amande. The intention and resolution to end Erica’s life if the situation called for it could be seen in her eyes.

“Got it... I won’t let anyone interrupt.”

Not the soldiers on the ground, nor the spirit arts user hiding to provide long-ranged support. Rio cast his attention across the area with his sharp gaze.

“These people are servants of Galarc nobles that have come to retrieve Liselotte Cretia! I shall inflict divine punishment upon them!”

With that declaration, Erica raised her bishop staff and charged at Aria. At the same time, Aria stepped forward to close the space between them. Once they were within reach of each other, they swung their weapons and began a fierce exchange. Erica had more physical strength, but Aria stood up to her with superior maneuvers and combat techniques.

Aria said that Saint Erica has a powerful physical body enhancement, but her movements are still those of an amateur. I agree—as long as no one hinders them, this match will be Aria’s.

Rio observed Erica’s movements from above and judged it safe to leave it to Aria.

“S-Support Saint Erica now! Apprehend that insolent woman!” Andrei ordered the soldiers gathered at the estate, attempting to block Aria’s movements with their numbers.

“Raaaargh!” The soldiers started charging at Aria from every direction. At this rate, the battlefield would become a disorderly mess.

Foreseeing their movements, Rio scattered the orbs of light he had set up around himself, raining them down on the soldiers from a height of ten meters. None of the orbs had enough force to kill unless they hit critical points, but they had enough force to send a large man flying several meters with a direct hit.

“Guh!”

“Whoa!”

Every single orb hit its mark, knocking the soldiers unconscious. In the span of a few seconds, more than a dozen soldiers fell to the ground. There were still soldiers on their feet, but...

“Eek...”

They faltered at the sight of their comrades being blown away by the rain of light that appeared out of nowhere. Once they realized that approaching Aria meant coming under Rio’s fire, their legs stopped. Rio replenished his light orbs as soon as he fired them, so their will to fight was whittled away.

“Wh-What are you doing?! Fight! If you can’t approach that brazen woman, aim for the man flying there. Release your spells, your arrows!” Andrei ordered the soldiers around him anew.

“Ngh...”

“Glacies Projectilis!”

Several people with the means to attack at a distance fired their bows and chanted spells for low-level attack magic, aiming them at Rio. He twirled in the air, spinning to get a 360-degree look at the ground. Once he confirmed where the scattered attacks were coming from, he sent all of his light orbs shooting off at the same time. The orbs darted erratically, as though they had minds of their own, as they chased down each attack spell and arrow. Some extra orbs even went to make a counterattack on the soldiers, knocking them unconscious.

“Wh-What is that man...?”

“How can a human float in the air?”

“What are those balls of light?”

Rio had gained complete control of his surroundings. Sensing that, the remaining soldiers on the ground lost their will to fight.

“Is there nothing we can do but watch...?” Andrei fell to his knees in despair.

With no one to interrupt them, the battle between Aria and Erica had grown more intense. Erica was still the stronger one in physical abilities, but it seemed like Aria had the winning edge. Her combat skills had allowed her to take the lead with counterattacks.

The fight was leaning in favor of Rio and Aria. If they continued like this, the outcome would be clear in a matter of minutes. But for some reason, the Saint had yet to enhance her physical body. Her hidden strength was still unknown.

Something’s strange. I’ve had control over the air this entire time, but the person who shot at Aishia hasn’t made any attempts to attack me.

Unlike when Aishia tried to escape with Liselotte, all aerial attacks had ceased. Rio had taken position in the air since he had been the most wary of the mysterious spirit arts user, so he found this quite strange.

“It seems I am at a disadvantage here after all. I can’t fight with all my strength.” Erica suddenly came to a stop on the ground.

“Refusing to accept your defeat?” Aria said, cautiously pausing.

“I cannot exert my power to the fullest. The citizens I should be protecting have fallen around me, writhing in pain. If I were to use my power under these conditions, they’d be killed. This man in the sky may seem like a gentleman, but his methods are rather cunning,” Erica said as she looked up.

Aishia, how are things over there? Anything strange? Rio asked, ignoring Erica.

Nothing yet. I’ve reached the southernmost edge of our communication range. In other words, she was roughly one kilometer south of Rio—a short distance out of the city, most likely.

All right. The spirit arts user that obstructed you has stopped attacking here. They may have gone your way, so be careful. We’re about to wrap things up here.

Okay.

With that, their transmission ended.

“Pretending I don’t exist? What a cold man,” Erica lamented from below.

“I don’t see the person that interrupted your escape before we arrived. I have a bad feeling about it—let’s retreat soon,” Rio said to Aria below as he ignored Erica’s words yet again.

“Understood,” Aria replied.

If she had to choose between fighting Saint Erica and securing Liselotte’s safety, she’d prioritize the latter. She wasn’t about to forget that through her hatred. Aria was still as calm as ever.

“Oh? Did you think you could escape so easily after making such a commotion on enemy grounds?” Erica raised her staff, grinning in defiance.

“You were the one who started it in our kingdom. You have no right to be criticizing others,” Aria snapped back immediately.

“Hehehe...”

Aria raised her sword, ready to stop Erica at a moment’s notice. But in the next moment, Rio launched all his light orbs at the ground, surrounding Aria in a cone shape. The wall of orbs separated Aria from Erica, and in that single instant Rio descended to the ground to pick Aria up in his arms.

“Let’s go.”

He rose into the air once more, continuing to an altitude of ten-odd meters high.

There still aren’t any attacks preventing our escape...

At the same time, there were no reports of a surprise attack from Aishia. Why? Rio racked his brain for a reason as he hurried to meet up with Aishia and Liselotte. Meanwhile...

So she can’t use her power fully with people around. But if she lets them leave the city, she’ll be helpless... What will the Saint do now, hmm?

From far above in the skies, Reiss was watching everything unfold.

◇ ◇ ◇

Meanwhile, in the estate garden immediately after Rio and Aria left, a dismal mood hung in the air. Everyone in the garden had just tasted what despair was like. It was their first defeat since the revolution, and it seeped into them like a poison. The Holy Democratic Republic of Erica was lacking in any real combat experience; most of the battles that took place during the revolution were won with Erica’s power—they were victories unachievable without her. Thus, the soldiers were far less proficient compared to the armies of other kingdoms. Their opponent this time was a bad matchup, but he had provided them a vivid lesson. They were completely underprepared. Utterly powerless.

“Aah! Oh, Saint Erica! Forgive me, forgive us! We were helpless against him! We were unable to do anything, leaving you to fight alone!” Andrei was as shaken as a man sinking in a swamp of despair, apologizing to Erica with everything he had.

“It’s all right, Andrei. Everyone else too. You all fought courageously.”

Erica gave them a kind, motherly smile and shook her head.

“Saint Erica!”

“Saint Erica!”

“Saint Erica!”

Everyone called Erica’s name, seeking salvation.

“Liselotte Cretia is a witch after all! A witch! She brought misfortune to this country! She is the symbol of disaster!” Andrei’s face twisted with murderous fury as he declared Liselotte’s existence as evil itself.

“I’m sorry. I was the one who brought her here. This was all because of my poor judgment.” Erica suddenly adopted a sorrowful look as she admitted her own mistake.

“No! Not at all! Who could have known? Who could have known that her gentle, saintlike demeanor hid her true face as a witch! She sympathized with the people and recited impressive words at us to win our hearts! That woman is a cunning witch!” Andrei insisted that Erica wasn’t to be blamed by expressing contempt for Liselotte.

“Those who invaded us today are the powers possessed by the evil noble class of a major nation. The evil we defeated through revolution was tiny in comparison. As long as huge nations like theirs exist, our country will always be in danger.”

“Oh, oooh! We were so ignorant, truly! How could we have been so foolish?!”

“You must not become conceited, Andrei. I’ve always reminded you—humans are foolish creatures.”

Andrei gasped, then looked even more regretful. “I was truly, truly foolish... How could I have been so blind...”

“But you must not forget this either: humans are only able to face their true selves when they face their despair. So face it! Learn, without running away! About yourself as a person, about your emotions that remain after the despair. Then use those emotions as fuel to step forward! Do you still have the will to keep moving? Democracy won’t progress without utterly crushing the noble class of the continent. You should be well aware of that. Will you let that stop you?! Do you still wish to make a world for the people?!” Erica raised her bishop staff high, fanning the emotions of her audience with her questions.

“I-I want to move forward!”

“We want to keep going!”

“But how can we?!”

“Do we have the power to do such a thing?!”

Those listening to her raised their voices.

“You do! I said this to them: did you think you could escape so easily after making such a commotion on enemy grounds? So don’t worry—you have me with you! Can you believe in me? In me, and in the miracles I’ve performed until now?!”

“Of course!”

“Without question!”

“I believe!”

“We’ll believe in you!”

“Me too!”

The voices gradually grew more lively.

“In that case, I shall show you another miracle today! I was planning on saving my power for invading the major nations, but it cannot be helped. A major nation has trampled all over our soil!”

With the bishop staff in her right hand, Erica spread her arms wide and looked up at the skies.

“Protector of the weak, the people, this nation! The greatest divine beast, the guardian beast, shall protect the people and slay all evil! Now is the time for judgment! I summon thee, beast of the land!”

A giant shadow immediately covered the inner courtyard like a cloud.

Chapter 6: Beast of the Land

It happened just as Rio flew out of Ericaburg with Aria in his arms. He had spotted Aishia and Liselotte hiding behind a boulder in the wasteland south of the capital, when—

“What?!” Rio felt a bizarre rise in magic essence from behind him. He turned back to face the capital in a panic.

“What...is that...?”

“Wha...”

Rio and Aria were both rendered speechless.

“...”

The two on the ground could see it as well; Liselotte was cowering with bated breath, and Aishia was glaring at it with a grim expression.

They were all staring at a four-legged beast that stood so tall it made the enormous black wyvern Rio had once fought seem small in comparison.

In a space of a hundred meters in diameter, particles of light were gathering to form a shape like a materializing spirit.

It wasn’t exactly the same, but its form resembled a rugged, ferocious fighting bull. Most of its exterior was covered in a rocklike surface, and three twisting, snake-headed tails extended from its rear. It was a creature beyond this world—a mythical beast.

Once the four-legged beast materialized in the air, it remained floating and stared down Rio and Aria from a kilometer away. Its eyes were filled with a hatred that couldn’t be described as mere rage.

“ROOOOOOOOOOOOOOOH!” An intense roar of fury shook the air across the nation.

Haruto...!

Aishia’s voice was in a rare fluster.

Yeah, that thing is bad! Rio replied as he quickly descended to her.

“You need to evacuate immediately!” He drew his sword, giving the three of them an order with a look of undisguised panic.

◇ ◇ ◇

Meanwhile, in the skies above Ericaburg, high enough for the four-legged beast to look minuscule in size...

Now that’s a roar that hasn’t been heard in a thousand years...

Reiss watched the four-legged beast materialize.

The saint has awakened after all. That means she’s obtained the right to step into the domain of transcendence, just once.

His gaze was quite serious.

I didn’t expect her to do so in this fight, but... Now that things have come to this, it’s time to see how much of a fight the Black Knight can put up against a divine beast.

The fierce battle would commence immediately after.

◇ ◇ ◇

“The three of you need to evacuate immediately!”

Just as Rio gave his order, the four-legged beast—no, the “beast of the land,” as Erica called it, glared at Rio and the others on the ground, before a powerful shell of magic essence appeared in its mouth. The condensed essence was about thirty meters in diameter.

This is bad! Rio immediately sent his essence into his sword.

“Hah!” The beast released its essence shell.

“Oh...” Before Liselotte knew it, the shell was closing in right before her eyes, and she could do nothing but tremble. She couldn’t even react. Meanwhile, Aria yanked Liselotte towards her in order to cover her.

“It’s okay,” Aishia said at the same time Rio swung his sword. The blade was coiled in a fierce, storm-like wind.

“Oh!”

The wind that was released with a diagonal slash from bottom left to top right cut down the essence shell. It wasn’t enough to reflect the shot, but it was enough to send it off course. The redirected shot landed several hundred meters behind them in the wasteland, exploding with a tremendous shock wave. There was enough momentum for a typhoon to reach the position where Rio and the others stood.

“Gah...” Liselotte staggered in place, but Aria supported her body. Fragments of broken earth from the center of the explosion flew their way too. Rio realized that, but before he could move, Aishia created a wall of wind to steer the boulders away from them.

“I’ll block them.”

Suddenly, the beast began flying at a speed unthinkable for its huge size. It made a beeline for Rio and the others outside of the city. Or so it seemed, when it turned to the right and put a kilometer of distance between them—but only for a few seconds. The movement speed of the huge beast had caused the atmosphere to shake, creating a violent wind. A cloud of dust was kicked up from the earth, but that was blocked by Aishia’s wall as well.

It changed locations? But why?

Rio was unsure of the reason why the beast had moved. However, he had no information to go off, so he was unable to make a guess.

“Vrah!” The beast of the land opened its mouth once more, and a tremendous amount of magic essence gathered again. This time, it was clearly more powerful than the first shot.

With that much magic essence, the attack will be beyond imagination...

If he moved rashly, he might not be able to protect everyone. With that judgment, Rio instantly yelled in a louder voice than ever before. “Once I block the second shot, Aishia will take you two and flee south! Run until you feel it’s safe!”

At the same time, he refined his own essence in order to confront the beast’s attack.

He drew out more of his power than he ever had before. The essence, which normally couldn’t be seen by normal humans, had become visible, but he didn’t have high hopes.

Can I really block this...?!

That was how great the essence the beast was condensing was. Rio didn’t have the confidence in himself to match that.

“That’s...” Seeing the pure light of magic essence flowing from Rio’s body, Liselotte and Aria’s eyes widened.

“Haruto, I’ll block the first shot with you,” Aishia said from behind Rio.

“All right... Please use all the magic essence you’ve got. I’ll go first, you join in once you’ve built up enough essence,” Rio replied without looking back.

“Okay.” Aishia nodded and hugged Rio gently from behind.

“...” Liselotte and Aria watched on in a daze.

The path between them allowed the essence sleeping within Rio to transfer to Aishia. Soon enough, Aishia’s body was also overflowing with essence that was visible to the human eye.

Just as the two enhanced their essence to the max, the beast of the land finished readying its attack.

“It’s okay. You can protect them, Haruto,” Aishia said softly, whispering into Rio’s ear.

“Thank you...”

That allowed Rio to snap to his senses, regaining some of his confidence. In order not to hinder Rio’s movements, Aishia took one step back and released him. Immediately after...

“RAAAAAAAAAAAH!” A piercing scream shook the air. Pure destructive energy was released from the beast of the land’s mouth. Energy that could disintegrate every material it touched, leaving not even dust behind.

“Haaah!” Against such an opponent, Rio tried to neutralize the attack with his own destructive energy. Two beams of destructive light collided with each other by the outskirts of the city.

“Wh-What...?” With Liselotte in her arms, Aria stood her ground using her physically enhanced body.

“They’re...evenly matched?” Liselotte squinted her eyes to see what was happening. However, she couldn’t process the situation at all; her vision was blinded white by the collision of light against light. Considering how the attack hadn’t reached them, they must have been able to compete with each other...

“I don’t know. It’s too hard to tell, but...!”

Aria couldn’t tell what was happening either. It took everything she had just to keep them from being blown away.

“R-Right! We can only believe in them!” Liselotte squeezed her eyes shut in prayer, clinging to Aria.

The current situation was like a back-and-forth pushing game. In other words, whoever wasn’t able to maintain their attack first would lose the push.

No matter how much magic essence slept within Rio’s body, activating arts and maintaining their activation required the action of refining essence and releasing it from the body.

It was impossible for even Rio to keep up an art of this scale for an extended period of time. His limit was quickly approaching, but Rio wasn’t alone right now.

“I’ve got enough essence now. Let’s push it back, Haruto,” Aishia’s voice echoed. She stood beside Rio and released her accumulated energy. To an onlooker, it would’ve seemed like the beast of the land’s beam was winning against Rio’s, but by combining their energies, Rio and Aishia tilted the balance of fate in their favor in a single moment. The beam from the beast of the land was repelled in an instant.

“AAAAAAH?!” The spirit art from the two of them enveloped the beast of the land.

“Now!” Rio yelled.

“Right!”

Aishia whipped around, grabbing Liselotte and Aria together. She then accelerated in a single burst of wind spirit arts.

“Oh!”

“Ugh...”

Aria’s body was strengthened through her enchanted sword, but the gravitational forces were rather painful for Liselotte’s unprotected body.

However, such speed was necessary to escape. While Rio was still maintaining the attack, Aishia took Liselotte and Aria away from the scene as fast as she could.

◇ ◇ ◇

Meanwhile, those in the center of the city were able to observe the collision of magic essence between Rio and the beast of the land. Though they were a fair distance from the outer wall, the shells of light that were several tens of meters in diameter were hot enough to bathe the city in a heated wind.

“Wh-Whoa...”

Those gathered in the garden of the government building were continuously rendered speechless by the unbelievable sight.

What... What is the meaning of this? How could the divine beast lose in power? There shouldn’t be any human strong enough to stop the divine beast. This isn’t right!

The situation was unexpected for Erica as well, whose eyes were wide. For the record, “divine beast” was the other name by which Erica referred to the beast of the land.

She had honestly thought things would be over with the first attack. That was her intention when she summoned it. Yet it had required an even stronger second attack. And just when she believed it was over this time, for some reason a stronger attack came firing back.

According to her expectations, Erica was meant to be rejoicing over the defeat of the formidable enemy outside the city right now.

Are you saying this boy’s strength is equal to the power of a major nation? There was no way I could have expected this. How many people in a major nation have this level of strength?

What if there were multiple people like this?

There may be difficult situations for me to win one-sidedly in the future. Is he a hero as well? Is that how he obtained power equal to mine? If so, my plan may be forced to deviate.

Many questions flashed through Erica’s mind.

“I must confirm for myself,” she muttered, and began walking towards the estate gate.

“P-Please wait, Saint Erica.” Andrei snapped back to his senses and called out to her.

“What is it, Andrei?”

“Where are you going?”

“To oversee the fight with my own eyes.”

The moment Erica uttered that, sounds of despair came from those standing around the garden.

“Ah! Aaah!”

The light beam from Rio and Aishia had enveloped the beast of the land.

“Agh!”

“Eek!”

“O-Our guardian beast!”

“It’s over!”

Everyone stooped over in fear, screaming in shock. They were completely convinced that the guardian beast had been defeated.

“Calm down, everyone! Do you not believe in me, in the miracle I have created?!”

Erica slammed the end of her bishop staff into the ground, calling out to everyone. The commotion immediately quieted as their gazes focused on her.

“B-But the guardian beast, the beast of the land has...” Andrei said on behalf of the others. His face was pale as a sheet as he glanced over at where the divine beast stood. The beam Rio had released had already faded, but a tremendous cloud of dust blocked their view in its place.

“It’s okay, the guardian beast won’t be defeated just like that,” Erica stated resolutely. “However, I may have misjudged the power of a major nation. That’s why I want to see it with my own eyes. If necessary, I will finish things with my own hands. Do not stop me.”

“I-In that case, I shall go too!”

Andrei immediately tried to follow Erica as she left, but—

“Andrei, you are the prime minister. Take control of the city in my place. You can help more by doing that than by following me.”

“I... I understand.”

Andrei was admonished by Erica. He bit down on his lip and nodded in frustration.

“Then please allow me to accompany you in Mister Andrei’s place!” Natalia offered firmly.

Erica sighed heavily. “Your life may be placed in danger... Are you prepared for that?” she asked.

“I am prepared! I am willing to sacrifice my life for you, Saint Erica. When will I fight if not now?”

Natalia expressed her desire to fight without fear. Then...

“Th-That’s right!”

“I’ll go too!”

“Me too!”

“And I!”

“Please allow us to go!”

The soldiers piped up in agreement.

“Fine... However, we must move as quickly as possible. Only those who can enchant their physical abilities and keep up like Natalia may come along. I’ll allow ten of you at most—you’ll be fighting if the need arises. I will go first.” Erica seemed to be in a hurry, as she started running without adding anything further.

“Augendae Corporis!”

Natalia used the magic artifact around her arm to increase her physical abilities and started after Erica. Others chanted the spell after her and chased behind them in scattered groups.

◇ ◇ ◇

After confirming that Aishia had taken Liselotte and Aria as far away from him as possible, Rio glared at the beast of the land instead of fleeing after them.

This guy’s magic essence hasn’t weakened at all.

As the rearguard, Rio began refining his own essence once again in preparation for a follow-up attack from the beast, concealed as it was by the huge dust cloud of destruction.

I have to defeat this thing here. I cannot allow it to go near the Galarc Kingdom.

He may have been able to flee with Aishia, but Rio had a reason to stay here and fight.

“Rah!”

Suddenly, three beams of light fired out of the dust cloud. Each beam was far weaker than the shells they’d fired at each other just now, but even then they were enough to burn the ground they touched. Each beam of light closed in on the point where Rio stood.

“Ah!” Rio broke into a run, using wind spirit arts to accelerate in a single burst. He slipped under the beams of light and closed in on the beast. The dust cloud covering the beast cleared with the wind.

Unharmed, huh...

Rio frowned grimly. The beast’s form was exactly the same as when Rio first saw it. The three tails that had snakelike heads were what had fired the three beams of light. Each tail swayed as though it had a mind of its own as they aimed for Rio.

It was quite a blow to know that the earlier attack hadn’t left a scratch, but Rio proceeded forward without hesitation. Just because he was scared didn’t mean he could run away.

He slipped past the rain of light beams and closed the distance to the beast, setting up several orbs of light around him, each measuring ten-odd meters in diameter. He then sent them flying towards the beast.

Each had enough power to demolish a castle wall with a direct hit, but seeing how it was unharmed after the earlier light battle, he didn’t have high hopes.

I doubt an attack of this level will have any effect, but...

When the snake tails saw Rio’s light orbs approaching, they changed the trajectories of their breaths to cut down the orbs.

It blocked the light orbs? Did that mean a direct hit would’ve caused damage? That was the thought that instantly passed through Rio’s mind.

...I want to see what happens when an attack hits.

The scale of their first attacks had been so huge he hadn’t been able to visually confirm the direct hit. The dust cloud had cleared to what seemed like an unharmed beast, so he thought he had failed to damage it. But why would it need to defend itself if so?

At this point, the distance between the two sides was less than a hundred meters. The size difference between them was like a human looking up at a castle.

“Rah!” The beast lifted a front leg and slammed it down in an attempt to crush Rio, and it immediately sounded as though a huge explosion had gone off. The area around the point of contact was folded upwards by the shock wave, shaking the entire surroundings.

If it had made a direct hit, even a human with a physically enhanced body would have died instantly, but...

“...”

With his sword held aloft, Rio had moved above the beast’s head. While floating with his spirit arts, he landed a direct hit against the back of its head with a wind-clad blade—

“URRAH?!” The beast stumbled, dropping towards the ground.

So it can be damaged after all...?

Rio clearly witnessed the attack make a direct hit, confirming that the back of its head was gouged open. However, he could see the wound heal itself cleanly right before his eyes. This left him unsure if it counted as true damage or not.

“Guh.”

In place of the head that was thrown off-balance, the three heads at the end of its tails snapped at Rio instead. Rio waited until the last moment to see through the abnormal movements of the tails, then twisted himself midair to avoid the attack.

“Vrah?!”

He landed on one of the tails and ran the tip of his sword from top to bottom, running along the tail. It split open like a neat scalpel cut.

Perhaps it could feel pain. A screeching roar filled Rio’s ears, but the wound was already stitching itself back together.

The other two tails snapped, trying to swallow Rio and the tail he was standing on whole.

“Gwah?!” The tail that was bitten squirmed in pain. The other two tails seemed to think they had bitten down on Rio, as they were chewing furiously.

However, Rio had already jumped onto the beast’s back. He watched the tails and launched two huge orbs of fire at them, directly hitting the heads of the tails.

“GWAAAH!” The two tails stopped chewing when they were shrouded in fire and started shaking themselves to extinguish the flames. At the same time, Rio put more magic essence into his sword.

“Haaah!”

He accelerated along the beast’s back with wind spirit arts, running towards its rear. As he approached the tails, he released a slash of light that was more than ten meters wide, slicing off the three tails at the base. He then leaped off the beast’s rear and immediately turned back to check the state of the wound.

How about that...?!

The three tails were all decapitated. However, all three were still moving, and began flying like long-bodied wyverns. On top of that, all three were automatically healing the damage Rio had dealt to them.

“Ngh...” The tails fired laser beams from their mouths at Rio. The beast’s main body also looked up at Rio and released five beams of light from its mouth. Each one had just as much power as the beams coming from the tails.

A total of eight beams of light tried to pierce through the air and cut Rio down. Rio changed his course of movement and jumped, evading the attacks.

It was difficult to evade eight beams while at close range, so he distanced himself for now. He stopped at around one kilometer from the beast, but at this size scale it still felt close.

Separating it from the body and allowing it to move freely is basically increasing the number of enemies. There’d be no end to things like this...

He was definitely doing damage with attacks of a certain scale. But the instant self-recovery was nullifying that damage. Up until this point, Rio had been one-sidedly dealing damage, but it was hard to say the battle was in his favor. It could hardly be called an even match.

If I get hit just once, I’ll be in trouble.

Eight beams of light fired at Rio incessantly, and evading them all was mentally wearing. What could he do? How could he prevail?

What is this thing, anyway? It suddenly appeared in the sky above the city. A spirit? But can spirits have this much power when they’re not in humanoid form? The saint is controlling it...right? If her secret power is to control earth, how can she create creatures like this? What is the ability hidden in her Divine Arms?

He considered possibilities of the beast’s identity in order to find its weaknesses, but he couldn’t settle on a conclusion. Rio desperately racked his brain as he dodged the beams.

I can’t see an end to that regenerative ability, but... Should I try to make another attack on the body? If I can behead the beast itself...

One idea filled his head—that there was no creature that could live with its head cut off. The heart was another weakness of a living creature, but it was hard to tell where the heart was located in a body this huge. That’s why he would aim for the neck—perhaps he could defeat it that way.

He sure hoped so.

However, in order to do that, he’d have to dodge the eight beams of light and approach the body again. It took all he had to evade them at this distance already, so it would be even more taxing to get closer.

On top of that, from the regeneration he’d observed until now, there was no guarantee that beheading it would be enough to defeat it. Just then—

Is that...the saint?

He spotted Saint Erica bursting out of the gate to the city. She had come running from the official estate with her body enhanced by her Divine Arms. Natalia and the others, who could only use the weaker physical ability enchantment, were still yet to arrive.

Is this beast being controlled by her after all?

The beast was so big, it wouldn’t be strange for the city to be affected by its attacks—yet it had been completely unharmed until now.

If she’s the one controlling it...

One possibility came to Rio’s mind. Perhaps if the saint died, the beast would disappear too. If the saint was in control, then that was a possibility. In fact, based on the situation, he was almost certain of this.

The battle would only get worse for him at this rate. And if the saint could control this beast, she could make it attack the Galarc Kingdom.

No choice but to try.

Rio readied himself. He rapidly altered his course to descend upon the saint by the city gate, and he didn’t neglect to keep refining magic essence in his body in order to deal with the beast’s attacks either. He was sending essence to his sword even as he evaded the attacks.

Just then, the beam of light aimed at Rio’s descent veered off to the sky. All eight beams started avoiding Rio. It was as though it was actively avoiding dealing any damage to the city.

The beast’s attack missed! I knew it! The hypothesis in Rio’s head changed to a certainty.

“...” Erica watched Rio descend with an eerie smile on her face. There was over a kilometer of distance between them, but right now Rio was moving at a speed that was pushing the limits of his body. At his speed, he could close that gap in less than ten seconds even while moving erratically to dodge the eight beams of light.

However, the divine beast wasn’t about to let Rio approach Erica without a fight. The main body and three tails moved with light steps unbefitting of its huge size, standing in the way of Rio to protect Erica and the city.

So fast...!

The divine beast’s speed was on par with Rio’s. Its enormous body that easily measured over a hundred meters could move around rapidly. The wind that blew around them was like a storm. But its directivity seemed to be controlled, as it sent a strong countercurrent in Rio’s direction.

It was the moment of truth. If he backed down here, the divine beast would interfere to protect Erica, leaving no hope of improving the situation. Letting it take position before the city meant the saint and her beast’s movements would be restricted. They would use fiercer attacks to draw Rio away from the city, making it even harder to approach.

Thus, this moment where his opponent had just gone on the defensive was his best chance. Rio activated his spirit arts to interfere with the stormy winds blowing against him. Repelling it would require a tremendous amount of magic essence, but he couldn’t use his essence excessively if he wanted to finish off the beast’s main body.

In other words, he had to secure a flight route and push his way through. Rio enhanced the wind barrier around him with that image in mind.

His speed towards the divine beast increased even further. The faster he went, the more his trajectory straightened out, but he wanted to close the distance before his opponent could ready itself as much as possible.

“Grah!” The divine beast’s main body suddenly resumed firing its light beam. The three tails also moved nearby, spitting their lasers out to block Rio’s descending approach.

“Ugh...”

In order to evade the eight thick beams of light, Rio started moving in a zigzag line. But the erratic movements on top of his maximum speed were quite a burden on his body, and his face twisted in pain.

The g-forces from his acceleration alone were strong enough—it was self-explanatory that additional acrobatic movements would make that burden heavier. However, failing to evade an attack would mean instant death. Rio maintained his speed while weaving between the beams, approaching the main body of the beast.

The distance to the divine beast was under a hundred meters. Only three or four seconds had passed since Rio began his approach. The closer he got to the beast’s mouth, the closer the beams of light merged together to form one thick laser.

It swallowed Rio up...or so it seemed. In the next instant, he used a wind spirit art to force his trajectory off by a 90-degree angle.

“Ngh...” The greatest forces of the battle yet were put on Rio’s body. But thanks to that, he was able to evade the attack.

He had moved to a position suited for cutting off the beast’s head. All that was left was to close in faster than the beast could react.

“Haaah!”

A glowing slash that was several tens of meters long fired towards the beast’s neck. A considerable amount of magic essence was required to chop off the neck of such a large enemy. Thus, the attack contained all the essence he had built up until now in a single burst.

Afterword

Hello everyone, this is Yuri Kitayama. Thank you for reading Seirei Gensouki: Spirit Chronicles 18 - Beast of the Land. I’m sure many of you reading this afterword are already aware, but I have very important news to tell you first.

Seirei Gensouki: Spirit Chronicles is getting an anime!

TMS Entertainment is the production company, and information regarding the main staff and cast has already been released. An official website and Twitter account have been created for the anime, so please look them up if you’re interested.

And so, I’m finally able to break the news to everyone...! It’s thanks to everyone’s support of the series that Seirei Gensouki has been blessed with an anime adaptation, so I’m grateful to you all from the bottom of my heart.

I’d also like to use this space to thank everyone involved in the making of this anime and this series up until now, including Riv and my editor, who have been with me for five years.

There’s more information to be released in the future, so please check the official site and Twitter for the anime. In celebration of volume 18’s release and the anime adaptation, Melonbooks is holding their third Seirei Gensouki exclusive shop.

Volume 19 of the novel will be on sale in spring, so please look forward to that as well!

How did you find volume 18? The flow of the story will make it hard to have slice-of-life scenes for a while, but I wrote all the daily life I wanted in the last volume so I’ll be able to charge into the serious scenes without reserve from here. The main story will make some big shifts in the future, so please continue to enjoy the novel version of Seirei Gensouki: Spirit Chronicles.

Let’s meet again in volume 19!

Yuri Kitayama

November 2020